Francis O. Cunningham Papers VHP2006/6
CCSU Veterans History Project
Francis O. Cunningham Papers
Bulk, 1941-1946
1941 - 1946, 2006
VHP2006/6
CCSU Veterans History Project
9.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
This collection details experience of Francis O. Cunningham serving with US Marine Corps during World War II. The collection contains video oral history interview and personal documents.
Cunningham, Francis O., 1918 -
Biographical/Historical note
Francis O. Cunningham was recruited in 1941, while in his senior year at UCONN, into the Marine Corps Officer Candidate Program. Upon his graduation from the university, he immediately went to Quantico, VA for 9 months of training. He was sent to the Pacific Theatre of operations in September of 1942, where he was stationed on American Samoa for nine months, as part of the 4th Raider Battalion. He was also part of the fighting on Bougainville, in Papua New Guinea, and in the Solomon Islands, before he was transferred back to San Diego, CA to train new marines. During his time spent back in the U.S. he married Mrs. Cunningham, whom he had been writing to while he was overseas. They married on a Monday morning, during Mr. Cunningham's travel leave, and he returned to San Diego on Tuesday. After their wedding, Mrs. Cunningham moved to San Diego, where they lived in a small apartment off base. Mr. Cunningham was then sent back overseas, where he was part of the 3rd Amphibious Corps, and took part in the Battle of Okinawa. The Cunningham's first child was born two days before the war ended. Mr. Cunningham was discharged from the Marine Corps in early 1946, and he and his wife returned to Connecticut.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
United States. Marine Corps. Amphibious Force, III.; United States. Marine Corps. Marine Raider Battalion, 4th.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Pacific Area
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2006/6.I
  - War Ration Book One, 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/6.I.1
  - War Ration Book Two, 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/6.I.2
  - War Ration Book No. 3, 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/6.I.3
  - Fuel Oil Ration, Class 4B Consumer Coupons, Jul. 2, 1945; VHP2006/6.I.4
  - Ration Stamps, 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/6.I.5
  - Certificate of Registrar from U.S. Office of Price Administration, May 2, 1942; VHP2006/6.I.6
  - Officers Town House Member's Card, May, 1944; VHP2006/6.I.7
  - The Officers' Mess Membership Card, May 23, 1944; VHP2006/6.I.8
  - Interview Synopsis, Mar. 10, 2006; VHP2006/6.I.9
- Series II: Multi-Media, VHP2006/6.II
  - Oral history interview, Mar. 10, 2006; VHP2006/6.II.1; 1.0 dvd; Cunningham, Darcey